questions = {
    'DSA': [
        {"question": "What is the runtime complexity of the binary search algorithm?", "options": ['O(n)', 'O(log n)', 'O(n^2)', 'O(1)'], "answer": 2},
        {"question": "Which of the following is an example of a divide-and-conquer approach?", "options": ['selection sort', 'insertion sort', 'bubble sort', 'merge sort'], "answer": 4},
        {"question": "Which algorithm helps to determine the shortest path in a graph?", "options": ['binary search', 'dijkstra algorithm', 'bellmann ford', 'backtracking'], "answer": 2},
        {"question": "Which data structure follows the Last In, First Out principle?", "options": ['stack', 'queue', 'linked list', 'array'], "answer": 1},
        {"question": "Which data structure offers direct access to elements using an index?", "options": ['stack', 'queue', 'linked list', 'array'], "answer": 4}
    ],
    'DBMS': [
        {"question": "Identify the NoSQL database from the following options:", "options": ['MySQL', 'MongoDB', 'PostgreSQL', 'SQLite'], "answer": 2},
        {"question": "What does DBMS stand for?", "options": ['Data of Binary Management System', 'Database Management System', 'Database Management Service', 'Data Backup Management System'], "answer": 2},
        {"question": "Which SQL clause is used to apply conditions on data retrieval?", "options": ['WHERE', 'SELECT', 'FROM', 'JOIN'], "answer": 1},
        {"question": "What is the main function of an index in database operations?", "options": ['To delete data', 'To update data', 'To speed up query retrieval', 'To insert data'], "answer": 3},
        {"question": "ACID is an important concept in databases. What does it represent?", "options": ['Atomicity, Consistency, Isolation, Durability', 'Access, Consistency, Integration, Durability', 'Atomicity, Concurrency, Isolation, Durability', 'Accuracy, Consistency, Isolation, Durability'], "answer": 1},
    ],
    'Python': [
        {"question": "Which keyword is used to define functions in Python?", "options": ['func', 'def', 'function', 'define'], "answer": 2},
        {"question": "What will be the output of: print(type([]))?", "options": ['list', 'tuple', 'dict', 'set'], "answer": 1},
        {"question": "Which Python keyword is used to define a class?", "options": ['def', 'class', 'object', 'function'], "answer": 2},
        {"question": "How can you add comments in Python code?", "options": ['//', '#', '/* */', '--'], "answer": 2},
        {"question": "What does 3**2 evaluate to in Python?", "options": ['9', '6', '5', '8'], "answer": 1},
    ]
}
